谢谢
Thank you.
注意
Hey, heads up!
该死  我说了注意
Shit. I said heads up.
伊妮德
Enid?
Enid.
你在外面干什么
What are you doing out here?
角落里还有一瓶水
There's another water bottle in the corner.
拿上就走吧
Take it and go.
你不回答我吗
You're not gonna answer me?
不
No.
亚历山大里怎么了
What happened in Alexandria?
我们听到了那声音
We heard that sound.
枪声
The gunfire.
伊妮德
Enid.
发生了总是会发生的事
What happened is what always happens.
人们死了
People died.
它们冲破了围墙吗
The herd broke through the walls?
谁
What herd?
尸群
The walkers.
它们提前冲出了采石场
They broke out of the quarry early.
我们引走了它们  但那汽笛声
We got on them, but that sound, the air horn,
是怎么回事
what was that?
那是人
It was people.
你该走了
You should go.
我妻子
My wife,
玛姬
Maggie,
她没事吧
she okay?
伊妮德
Enid?
玛姬没事吧
Is Maggie okay?
回答我
Answer me!
伊妮德
Enid.
Enid!
伊妮德
Enid.
Hey, Enid!
伊妮德
Enid!
《行尸走肉》
摩根
Morgan.
早上好
Morning.
我们还没聊过  我们该聊聊
We haven't talked. We should.
晚点聊  好吗
A little later, okay?
好
Okay.
你没必要经常上来
You don't have to be up here so much.
我不会的
I won't be.
这是他回来的方向
This is the direction he'd come in.
如果他发信号  就会在那边
If he sends up a signal, it'll be from out there.
或者不会有信号了
Or it-- it won't be.
我们出去时
When we go out there,
从来都不容易  不轻松
it's never easy, it's never simple.
总会有战斗
It's always a fight.
但更难的情况我们都挺过来了
But we've come back from harder things.
更远的距离我们也回来了
From further away.
格伦  达里尔
Glenn, Daryl,
亚伯拉罕和萨沙  他们也可以的
Abraham, and Sasha, they will, too.
也许我们不应该干等着他们回来
Maybe we don't wait for them to be back.
我们应该开始想想怎样把行尸引走
We should start figuring out how to draw the walkers away.
我们的食物和水还能支撑一段时间
We have some food and water to last us a while
墙也还撑得住
and the walls are holding.
我们可以慢慢来
We can take our time.
好好想清楚  把这事干好了
Really think this through. Do it right.
清理干净  这样他们就能...
Clear it so they can--
他们就能直接走进来了
they can walk right in.
我有天看见朱迪思在屋子里
I saw Judith in the house the other day.
她开始...
She's starting to--
她开始长得像洛莉了
she's starting to look like Lori.
-是啊  -这让我挺开心的
- Yeah. - Made me happy.
我也是
Me, too.
(贝琪  亲爱的  如果你在看这张纸条  那说明我没能活着回去)
(今日1点  在太阳能板处  举行祈祷圈活动)
爸
Dad.
你初次尝试还是用手枪比较好
Handguns will be a little better for your first go.
装弹  上膛
Magazine release. Slide release.
拇指保险
Thumb safety.
那算简单的  是不是  老爸
That stuff's easy, right, Dad?
没错  空的弹夹
Yeah. Empty magazine.
-空的枪膛  看到了吗  -看到了
- Empty chamber. See it? - Yeah.
有人在你前面  他们手里有枪
Someone's in front of you, they have a gun.
你会害怕的
You're gonna be scared.
你会的
You will be.
你的身体会紧绷  你没时间思考
Your body's gonna tense, you won't have time to think.
当你面对这种情况时
You're just gonna want to pull the trigger
会只想着扣下扳机
when you get it in front of you.
但你会打偏
But you'll miss
然后你就会死
and you'll be dead.
你得把枪举到与眼睛平行的地方
You have to get it up to your eye.
你得足够坚强  耐心等到一个好时机
You've got to be strong enough to wait for your moment.
我能...
Can I, uh...?
你的手指不能碰扳机
Hey, your finger doesn't touch the trigger
除非你准备好开枪了
until you're ready to shoot.
那把枪你留着吧
Keep that one with you.
体会体会随身配枪是什么感觉
Get a feel of what it's like to carry one around.
我能开枪吗
Can I shoot it?
也许可以朝着行尸开枪什么的
Maybe like down at the walkers?
不行  照现在的情况
No, with things how they are,
墙足够坚固能抵挡
the walls are strong,
但幸运的是行尸慢慢散开了
but we're lucky the walkers are spread out.
我们可不想把它们全部引到一个点
We don't want to pull them all to one spot.
那...在镇中心练习打靶可以吗
Well, what about, like, target practice in the center of town?
因为那样声音就会四散开来
'Cause then the sound will spread out in each direction.
或者我们可以安个消声器之类的东西
Or maybe we could use, like, silencers or something like that.
不过...
But, uh...
我们现在最好还是别浪费子弹
I mean, we probably don't want to waste bullets right now, huh?
只是想多学一点
Just want to learn more.
你会的
You will.
抱歉
Hey. Sorry.
我正在做...
I was making--
你想来点燕麦粥吗
you want some oatmeal?
多谢  不用了
Thank you. I'm-- I'm okay.
我看你刚刚在门边晃悠  有什么事
You were coming to the door. What's up?
需要我看看你手臂上的伤吗
Want me to take a look at your arm?
不  我来不是为了...
No, I'm not here for--
我没事
I'm fine.
有事可以告诉我
You can tell me if you're not.
摩根
Morgan.
现在方便谈谈吗
Can we talk now?
怎么了
What's going on?
在我回来的路上...
When I was coming back...
我试图用车挡住行尸
I tried to cut off the herd with the RV.
引开它们
Lead the walkers away.
但有五个额头上刻着W的人
But five of those people with the Ws in their foreheads,
把我拦下了
they stopped me.
他们想杀我  朝车子开枪
They tried to kill me, shot up the RV.
卡萝尔告诉我  她看到你
Now, Carol says she saw you.
不愿意杀死他们
That you wouldn't kill those people.
是你放走他们的吗
Did you let any of them go?
是的
Yes, I did.
我不想杀死五个我没必要杀的人
I didn't want to kill five people I didn't have to kill.
可他们活活烧死人啊
They burned people alive.
我知道
Yeah.
瑞克  在金恩郡那会儿
Why didn't you kill me, Rick,
你为什么不杀我
back in King County?
我对你亮刀  试图捅你
Pulled a knife on you. I stabbed you.
那你为什么不杀我
So why didn't you kill me?
是因为你从医院出来后我救了你吗
Was it 'cause I saved you after the hospital?
因为我知道你的为人
'Cause I knew who you were.
那会儿我一看见你就会杀你
Back there I would have killed you as soon as look at you.
我也动手了
And I tried.
但你饶了我一命
But you, you let me live
才有了后来我帮助亚伦和达里尔脱险
and then I was there to help Aaron and Daryl.
看吧  如果我不在场...
See, if I-- if I wasn't there...
如果他们死了...
if they died...
那些狼或许就不会来这里了
maybe those wolves wouldn't have been able to come back here.
我已经分不清对错了
I don't know what's right anymore.
因为我明明就很想杀死他们
'Cause I did want to kill those man.
看到他们为非作歹  恶性不改
I seen what they did, what they'd keep doing.
我明知可以了结此事
I knew I could end it.
但我也知道人是可以改变的
But I also know that people can change.
因为在座的每位都改变了
'Cause everyone sitting here has.
所有生命都是宝贵的
All life is precious.
而那个想法  那个想法改变了我
And that idea-- that idea changed me.
让我重获新生  让我活下去
It brought me back and it keeps me living.
我只是觉得  没那么容易
I just don't think it can be that easy.
-并不容易  -我的意思不是...
- It's not easy. - I wasn't saying...
我知道
I-- I know.
我想过要放弃那种想法
And I've thought about letting that idea go.
但我不愿意
But I don't want to.
也许你必须放弃
You may have to.
事情没有说起来那么简单
Things aren't as simple as four words.
从来没有过
I don't think they ever were.
你觉得我不该留在这里吗
Do you think I don't belong here?
现在这样做
Making it now,
你真以为你能手不沾血吗
do you really think you can do that without getting blood on your hands?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果我们能想办法到墙外去
If we can somehow get outside the walls,
回到采石场的车子那里
get back to our cars at the quarry,
我们就能用车子引走它们
we could use them to draw them away.
我们要建立更多哨点
We'll set up more watch points.
协调射击枪支和信号弹
Coordinate the shooting of guns and flares
这样就能把它们分散引走
so we could pull them out in even directions.
我们得用上所有我们的人
We'd need to get all our people on it.
卡尔  塔拉  罗西塔  卡萝尔
Carl, Tara, Rosita, Carol.
其他人呢
What about everybody else?
目前我们先不告诉别人
Well, let's just keep this to our own for now.
真的吗
Really?
如果我们有时间带上大家  那当然可以
Look, if we had the time to bring the people along, sure.
但我们连歇口气的机会都没有过
But we haven't had a chance to catch our breath.
真的吗
Really?
我们都在这个社区里
We're in here together.
现在我们正在歇息
We're catching our breath right now.
其他的都是借口
Anything else is just excuses.
迪安娜
Deanna.
瑞克
Rick.
那是什么
What's that?
扩张计划
Plans for the expansion.
我们现在有其他的事情要忙
We got a few other things on our plate right now.
我知道
I know.
事情结束之后  可以这样建设亚历山大
These are for what Alexandria can be after this.
因为不管怎样
Because one way or another,
这事都会结束
there's gonna be an after this.
刀砍进去后  不要立刻拔出来
Now, when the blade connects, don't jerk it right back.
-你会被卡住  -被卡住
- You'll get stuck. - Stuck?
就像斧子砍进树里
Like an ax cutting into a tree.
把刀砍进骨头容易  拔出来难
It's easier to get a blade into bone than out.
那应该怎么办
So what should we do?
用砍刀顺着伤口向下划出去
You should slide the machete down through the wound.
动作要连续
One fluid motion.
像这样划过骨头
Okay, you ease it through the bone like this.
懂了吗
All right?
我是个手握砍刀的武器菜鸟
I'm a weapons novice holding a significant blade here
我周围有人穿着露脚面的鞋
and there are people in my proximity with open-toed shoes.
是啊  所以振作点
That's right. So get a grip.
你在怕什么呢
What are you so scared of?
大概是死吧
That would be dying.
死很容易
Dying is simple.
一切都停止了  你死了
It all just stops. You're dead.
你周围的人死去
The people around you dying,
才是最难的
that's the hard part.
懂了吗  因为你继续活着
Okay? 'Cause you keep living
心里想着他们已经死了
knowing that they're gone
而你还在这里
and you're still here.
你最应该害怕的是继续活着
What you should be scared of is living
同时心里愧疚着自己没能尽力保护好他们
knowing that you didn't do everything you could to keep them here.
难受得坚持不下去了吗
Too upset to keep going?
噪音吓着你了吗
Are the noises scaring you
我能继续讲课了吗
or can I get back to my lesson?
我们再来一遍
Let's try this again.
你在干什么
The hell are you doing?
我要带你回家
I'm taking you home.
我不认识你
I don't know you.
那你为什么给我水喝
Why did you give me water?
我有水  你需要水
I had it, you needed it.
这不代表我们是朋友
That doesn't make us friends.
我们不是朋友  我是因为玛姬才这么做的
We're not friends. I'm doing this for Maggie.
你的妻子吗
Your wife?
她不会抛下你
She wouldn't leave you behind.
她肯定也不希望我抛下你
She wouldn't want me to leave you behind.
所以我们走吧
So we're going.
我和你妻子也不是朋友
I'm not friends with your wife either.
我不想跟你商量
I'm not having this conversation.
我不会把你丢在这里
I'm not leaving you out here.
我们现在就走
We're going now.
不
No.
把枪给我  伊妮德
Give me the gun, Enid.
转身走开
Turn around and walk away.
你不会开枪的
You're not gonna pull the trigger.
如果你逼我的话  我会的
I will if you make me.
放手
Let go.
混蛋
Asshole.
你拿枪指着我还叫我混蛋
You point a gun at me and I'm the asshole?
我们走
Let's go.
走后门去小巷
Out the back down the alley.
我们走大路  需要开阔的视野
We're taking the road. We need visibility.
为什么
Why?
因为半数尸群离开了
Because half the herd broke off
它们正在往家走
and they're headed towards home.
我猜你没碰上吧
I guess you missed that.
带路吧
Lead the way.
你看上去需要一些帮助
You look like you could use some help.
我觉得我们可以给这玩意儿造一个支架
You know, I think we could build up a brace on this thing.
怎么了
What?
你觉得你妻子不希望我杀了它吗
Think your wife wouldn't have wanted me to kill it?
我们可以利用它们引开行尸
We can use them to distract them.
灌木丛中有一个氦气罐
There's a helium tank in those shrubs.
还有更多气球和绳子
More balloons, more string.
只要支撑好  墙就没事
It don't mean anything as long as we keep this up.
我们刚见到你时
You know, you scared the
你把大家都吓了一跳
hell out of people when we first saw you.
我知道
I know.
你把我吓了一跳
You scared the hell out of me.
大胡子
With that beard.
你环顾四周的方式
The way you looked around
好像你看到了什么...
like you were seeing things we weren't...
我们没看到的事
hiding around corners.
结果真的是这样
Turns out you were.
本来这里节奏很慢
Things moved slow here.
然后你一来  一切都加快了步伐
And then things just started moving fast.
太快了
Too fast.
但不要放弃我们
But don't give up on us.
你在家里的时候跟谁住
Who did you stay with back home?
那不是我的家
It's not my home.
我住在奥利维亚那儿
I lived in Olivia's place.
但我靠我自己
But I was on my own.
行尸夺走了我的父母
Orphaned by walkers.
我也是
Me, too.
应该吧
Probably.
事情就是这样
It's just what happens.
我知道你很害怕
I get that you're scared.
我不怕
I'm not scared.
你是很怕
Yeah, you are.
你不想再失去什么了
You don't want to lose anything again,
所以你放弃了  说"事情就是这样"
so you give up and you say, "That's just what happens."
-我不需要说教  -我觉得你需要
- I don't need a lecture. - Yeah, I think you do.
你通过活下去来尊重死者
You honor the dead by going on.
即使当你害怕的时候
Even when you're scared.
你活着是因为他们牺牲了
You live because they don't get to.
因为害怕就举着枪
You think your parents wanted you
你觉得你父母会想让你那样吗
waving around a gun because you're afraid?
我们不必聊天
We don't have to talk.
糟糕
Crap.
天啊
My God.
别走
Stop.
我说了别走
I said stop.
有什么意义
What's the point?
世界在自取灭亡
The world is trying to die.
我们不应该去插手
We're supposed to just let it.
不
No.
你错了
You're wrong.
我们应该阻止它
We're not supposed to let the world die.
而且我肯定也不会让你死
And I sure as hell am not gonna let you die.
我肯定你妻子会原谅你的
I'm sure your wife will forgive you.
我不再是为了她才这么做
It's not for her anymore.
墙还没有倒
Look, the walls are still up.
房子也还在
The houses are still up.
我们会找到其他人的
We'll find out the rest.
好吗
Okay?
怎么回事
What the hell?
斯宾塞
Spencer.
斯宾塞  回来
Hey, Spencer, get back here!
塔拉
Tara.
斯宾塞
Spencer.
斯宾塞  快给我回来
Spencer, get back here now.
斯宾塞  快爬
Spencer. Spencer, move!
快  继续爬
Go! Keep moving!
-快点  -尤金
- Hurry! - Eugene...
让玛姬和罗西塔从岗哨处开枪
have Maggie and Rosita fire their guns out from their posts.
-为什么  -照做就是
- Why? - Just do it!
-塔拉  我良心会不安的  -快去
- Tara, I cannot in good conscience-- - Just do it!
斯宾塞  上来
Spencer, come on!
抓紧
Grab on!
塔拉  你已经为这些人差点死过一次了
Tara! You almost died once for these people.
-什么  -你他妈的在干什么
- What? - What the hell were you doing?
丢了只鞋  该死
Lost a damn shoe. Crap.
你刚在干什么
What was that?
我在帮忙  想找辆车引开它们
I was trying to help. I wanted to get to a car, draw them away.
你之前这样爬过吗
You ever make a climb like that before?
你想帮忙的话  就不要让我们反过来救你
You want to help? Don't make us come running to save you.
有什么主意  你先给我说
You got an idea, you come to me.
你会听我的吗
Would you have listened to me?
现在没事了吗
Everything okay now?
解决了
It's handled.
没事了
Everything's fine.
我的小抄
Cheat sheets.
没错
Yeah.
估计没能给你多少信念
Probably doesn't give you a lot of faith.
我还有信念
I have faith.
必须有信念不是吗
Well, you have to, right?
不是必须  是我选择的
You don't have to. I choose to.
你也该这样
You should, too.
这次你会告诉我你来干什么吗
So are you gonna tell me why you're here this time?
社区的抗生素库存如何
How well is the community stocked with antibiotics?
够用
We're good.
我得包扎伤口
I need to dress a wound,
但我不知道有没有感染
but I don't know if it's infected.
没必要的话我不想浪费药物
I don't want to waste medicine if I don't have to.
烧热红脓痛
FWoPP'RS.
发烧  发热  脓  疼痛和发红
Fever, warmth, pus, pain, redness...
告诉我是什么
Tell me what it is.
水肿
Swelling.
让我看看你的手臂
Let's take a look at your arm.
我早上没来
I didn't come in this morning
因为我不想让你卷入到
because I didn't want to get you involved in something
你或许不愿卷入的事
that you may not want to be involved in.
那是个保密
In a secret.
不是我的伤口
It's not my wound.
我知道你早上才照看了朱迪斯
I know you just took care of Judith this morning,
但斯宾塞那事之后
but they want some help with the watch points
哨岗需要人手  你能不能...
after that thing with Spencer. Could you...?
好的  没问题
Oh, yeah, no problem.
除非你想让我替你的班
Unless you want me to take your shift.
不用  我喜欢在上面
No, I like being up there.
即使那么多行尸在外面吗
Even with all them outside?
你能看到一切  包括里面
You can see everything. Even inside.
我把这些先放好
Um, let me just lock these up.
你能稍等会儿吗
Can you give me a second?
-你要进来吗  -好的
- Do you want to come in? - Yeah.
卡萝尔
Carol?
Carol.
怎么了  山姆
What, Sam?
山姆
Sam?
要是你接受不了怎么办
What happens if you can't live with it?
我告诉过你  那会打垮你
I told you, it eats you up.
你能下来吗  我听不清你说话
Can you come down here? I can barely hear you.
来的那些人
The people who came,
他们是怪物吗
were they the monsters?
我爸爸变成怪物了吗
Did my dad turn into one?
什么
What?
如果你杀了人
If you kill people,
你会变成怪物吗
do you turn into one of the monsters?
只有杀人才不会变成怪物
The only thing that keeps you from becoming a monster is killing.
-谢谢帮忙  -小事一桩
- Thank you for this. - Oh, yeah, no problem.
再见
Yeah. Bye-bye.
你在里面关着谁
Who the hell do you have in that cell?
见到丹妮斯了吗
Hey, you seen Denise?
没有
No.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
听着  之前的事我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry about before.
-我只是...  -他很蠢  这点我们知道
- I was just-- - He was stupid. That we know.
我的意思是  你不必为他那样做
I just meant what you did for him, you didn't have to.
我知道
I know.
你有可能会死掉
You could have died.
我想说我想过这点
I mean, I'd like to say I was thinking about it,
但我没有
but I wasn't.
所以你才那样做吗
Is that why you did it?
因为你没好好想过
You weren't thinking about it?
不  我们就该这样
No, that's how it works with us.
我们离不开彼此了  对吧
We're stuck with each other, right?
瑞克  你救了我儿子
Rick, you saved my son.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢塔拉吧
Thank Tara.
我已经谢过了
I already did.
现在我要感谢你
Now I'm thanking you.
斯宾塞做的事很蠢
What Spencer did was stupid.
我没法反驳这点
I can't argue that.
-至少他试过  -这不是重点
- At least he tried. - That's not the point.
我才是真有可能试过
I could have tried.
当时有机会
There was a chance.
什么意思
How's that?
行尸追他时  出现了空隙
When the walkers were going for him, it made a gap.
我可以跳下去  跑出去
I could have jumped down, ran, made it out.
我可以坐上车
I could have got in a car,
用车引走行尸
used it to lead the walkers away.
我可以那样做  然后斯宾塞就死了
I could have done that and Spencer would be dead.
但是你没有那样做
But you didn't do that.
为什么
Why?
我救他是因为他是你儿子
I helped save him because he's your son.
答错了
Wrong answer.
那是格伦  那是格伦
That's Glenn. That's Glenn.